23. The Ancient Art of the Brush Throughout its long history, writing has been
a big deal in China. Since the earliest dynasties, the skills of reading and writing have been
highly respected. In fact, they form an important part of the Chinese art world. Calligraphy,
the art of writing with a brush, is almost as old as writing itself. And though this
art form dates back thousands of years, it is still extremely popular today.
How did writing become so important in Chinese culture? The answer most likely lies way back
in the Shang dynasty, about 1600 to 1046 B.C. That's when characters were first carved
in bronze and used in religious events. This practice conveyed a spiritual aspect which
gave writing authority in the eyes of ordinary people. Calligraphy spread during the Han
dynasty, when the necessary tools and materials became more widely available. First there
was the brush, made from bamboo and animal hair. Early ink, or lamp black, was made by
burning pine wood and mixing it with water. Early forms of paper were invented around
AD 105. Finally, there was inkstone, a smooth piece of stone used for mixing ink. Together,
these tools were known as the four treasures of study in ancient China. Calligraphy has
been popular in China for thousands of years. Some say that it's an even higher art form
than painting. Though foreigners may not always get it, there's something truly special about
calligraphy. Every written character has a strict stroke order. When viewing the results,
you can trace the artist's process, reliving every stroke of his or her brush. This allows
for an intimate connection between artist and audience. Calligraphy is something that's best
experienced by doing. Luckily, this ancient art is still widely practiced today. So,
what are you waiting for? Get out there and find yourself a teacher.